Geoffrey BERGERET French Nationality 24 Year old

System & DevOps Engineer

« Divide and Rule »

+44 7842 783612 contact@gbergeret.org www.gbergeret.org

Profile

By experience, I acquired lots of skills in several business like: IT Developer, System Administrator or Network Engineer. Now my goal is to specialise myself in IT infrastructure: installation, exploitation, supervision, support and particularly sizing.

Work Experience

System and DevOps Engineer at Contentment – 10/2015 to now

- In charge of all System and DevOps part, sizing the infrastructure and support it.
- Migrate and automate the deployment of the existing architecture in AWS with Docker.
- Basically make things work and improve it...

Network Engineer (Apprentice) at Orange SA – 09/2012 to 09/2015

- VPN production automation (B2B) by implementing scripts (in Perl).
- Network support (second line) for routing, QoS, LAN on border side.

System Administrator (Part-time) at SHPS SARL - 02/2011 to 01/2014

- In charge of production the servers: security, installation, automation and deployment.
- Improve services and working environment with: LAMP, SVN, OpenVPN, Proxmox...
- Technical support (second line) to solve customer tickets.

Web Developper (Trainee) at Sales Conquest – 04/2011 to 06/2011

- Plugin import/export development for an e-commerce website (PHP/MySQL).

Education & Training

2015: Master of Science in Computer and Network Engineering (1st class) at ESIPE

Achievements: - transbubbles: Web plate-forme used to translate comics online.

- dmchecker: Project to apply unit tests "JUnit" on Java sources.
- docmycode: Equivalent of "Doxygen" implemented in C for C sources.

2011-2012: Master of Science in Computer Engineering (1st class) *at* UTBM Stopped to prioritise professional experience with apprenticeship training.

2011: Two years technical degree in Computer Sciences at IUT in Belfort

Achievements: - TZAAR: TZAAR plate-forme game adaptation in Java.

- Cryptography algorithm implementation in Python(RSA, ElGamal, ...).

Languages Skills

French -> Native

English —> Professional working proficiency (B2 — TOEIC 795)

German —> Elementary proficiency

Technical Skills

Networking: Routing (OSPF, BGP), VRRP, OpenVPN, DHCP, DNS

Infrastructure: Docker, AWS, Proxmox, Cisco, Firewall (pfsense, ipables)

System & Scripting: Linux, Shell (Bash, Zsh), Perl, Python, LAMP, SSH

Database: MERISE, ORM, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Web Developpement: PHP, (x)HTML, CSS (less), Laravel, Jekyll (Liquid)

Software Developpement: UML, Java, C/C++, Subversion, Git, CI/CD (drone.io)

Management Skills Project Management Team organisation Conduct training Independent Facilitate meeting Seminar facilitator

Hobbies Jogging Fitness Motorcycle
Travelling Cooking Brunch